准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
坏东西
分镜总监
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
水母田
没捉到
Missed ya
你不该在大马路上玩的  小朋友
You shouldn't play in the street, little guy
不然会被撞的
You could get run over
土东西
"The ild ones"
好怪的名字
That's a strange name
完蛋
Scallop
再见  土东西
Bye, ild ones
我喜欢你们呆呆的名字
I like your silly name
W
"W"
原来他们不是土东西
They're not "the ild ones"
一定是坏东西
They must be the wild ones
坏东西吗
The wild ones?
真该死
Tarnation
不知道坏东西是谁吗  小子
Don't you know who the wild ones are, son?
确实
No
我也不认识你
I don't know who you are, either
他们可是海底最残暴嗜血的飞车党
Why, they're the most ferocious
bloodthirsty biker gang under the sea
用一个下午就摧毁了整座城市
They've destroyed entire cities in an afternoon
嗜血飞车党
Bloodthirsty bikers
裤头村
50里
他们还朝着裤头村过去了
And they're headed straight for Bikini Bottom
我得去警告大家
I've got to warn everybody
最好走捷径
I better take the shortcut
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你到底从哪冒出来的
Where in the blue barnacles did you come from?
没空问这个了  蟹老板
There's no time for that, Mr. Krabs
找点重的东西来
Grab something heavy
堵住大门
Bar the door
拿木板封窗户
Board up the windows
一定要保护蟹堡王
We've got to protect the krusty krab
蟹黄堡必须活下去
The Krabby Patties must survive
别急  小子
Settle down, son
你这是发什么神经
What are you all riled up about?
飞车党
Bikers
来了
coming
龌龊
Nasty
残暴
ferocious
占
Take
领
over
镇子
town
摧毁
Destroy
快躲起来
Let's hide
你这是胡说八道什么
What are you going on about--
飞车党吗
bikers?
坏东西要来了  蟹老板
The wild ones are coming, Mr. Krabs
他们可是全海洋最残暴的饕餮混混
They're the most vicious, ravenous
horde of hooligans in the sea
你说饕餮吗
"Ravenous," did you say?
所以是形容他们贪吃是吧
That's another word for "hungry," isn't it?
欢迎坏东西
欢迎  坏东西
Welcome, wild ones
想把他们轻轻松松引进来
They'll be drawn here like a sailor to a tattoo parlor
就得加个特制摩托停车场
With a special biker parking
还有逼真的飞车党装饰
And authentic biker decor
上面有真正的血迹
With real bloodstains
最后还有
And, to top it off
定制摩托堡
a custom chopper patty
最棒的就是
And, best of all
我要涨价150%
I'll raise me prices 150%
到时候一定会赚大钱
I'll make a fortune
蟹老板  事情很严重
Mr. Krabs, this is serious
得给那小子放个假
That kid needs a vacation--
不过肯定不带薪
unpaid, of course
裤头村
25里
章鱼哥
Squidward
怎么了  海绵宝宝
Yes, SpongeBob?
有一伙叫做坏东西的飞车党要来了
A horrible biker gang called the wild ones are coming
得马上就跑
We've got to run
躲起来
Hide
天啊
Oh, my
听着好严重啊
This sounds serious
幸好我知道你应该要怎么办
Luckily, I know just what you should do
仔细听好
Listen closely
抓紧你的裤子
Get a good grip on your pants
转身
Turn around
这样吗  章鱼哥
Like this, Squidward?
就这样
That's it
派大星
Patrick
你好  海绵宝宝
Hello, SpongeBob
派大星
Patrick
有一伙邪恶的飞车党
An evil bunch of bikers
要来蹂躏裤头村了
are coming to ravage Bikini Bottom
派大星  没听到我刚刚说的话吗
Patrick, didn't you hear what I said?
听到了
I heard you
不过你好那句我没听到
But what I didn't hear was a "hello"
你好  派大星
Hello, Patrick
你好  海绵宝宝
Hello, SpongeBob
嗜血飞车党
Bloodthirsty bikers
我们必须躲起来
We've got to hide
你是怎么了
What happened to you?
我
I--
我一点都不想提
I don't want to talk about it, man
掩护我
Hide me
不对  掩护我
No, hide me
掩护我
Hide me
我
Me
不对  我
No, me
我
Me
不行
No
别再跑了
No more running
什么
What?
那伙飞车党自以为凶狠
Those bikers think they're so tough
穿着皮帽皮裤
with their leather hats and their leather pants
还有皮袜
And their leather socks
我们要是那样子打扮
If we dressed up like that
就是又大又可怕的飞车党了
then we'd be the big, scary bikers
而他们就是幼稚小笨蛋了
and they'd be little baby doo-doo heads
说得太对了  派大星
Say that again, Patrick
再  说  一  遍
幼稚小笨蛋
Little baby doo-doo heads
不对
No, no
不是那句
Not that part--
是打扮成又大又可怕的飞车党那句
the part about dressing up like big, scary bikers
高菲高伯
你觉得怎么样  派大星
What do you think, Patrick?
我样子凶狠不
Do I look tough?
我不会欺负你的
I wouldn't mess with you
我也不会  我的朋友
Nor I with you, my friend
飞车去吧
Let's ride
不用怕
Fear not
没必要恐慌
There is no need to panic
裤头村坏小子来了
The Bikini Bottom bad boys are here
我这下有安全感了
I feel protected now
这车看着就挺凶的
Those are some mean-looking rides, dudes
派大星  成功了
Patrick, it's working
他们以为我们是
They think we're--
残暴飞车党
Vicious bikers
蟹堡王
欢迎坏东西
裤头村  你们的救星来了
Bikini Bottom, your salvation is here
看吧
See?
派大星  那是你的口水
Patrick, that's your salivation
[ salivation（唾液分泌）
与 salvation（救星）谐音 ]
那么章鱼哥
So, Squidward
你准备好尽自己的本分了吗
are you ready to do your part?
是不是还要我嘲笑你们两个啊
Does that part include laughing at you?
因为你们俩样子比平常还要傻
Because you two look even more idiotic than usual
我们样子不残暴嗜血吗
Don't we look vicious and bloodthirsty?
我挺嗜血的
I'm bloodthirsty
血
看吧
See?
要喝吗
Want some?
不用
Oh, no
谢了  派大星
thank you, Patrick
我只喝无糖的血
I'm drinking diet blood
无糖血
看吧  章鱼哥
See, Squidward?
我们做一套  真能说一套吗
We walk the walk, but can we talk the talk?
你要不要加入我们的飞车党
So, you want to join our biker gang?
才不要
No, I don't
那我们的飞车俱乐部呢
What about our biker club?
不要
No
那我们的飞车组织呢
How about our biker organization?
不要
No
我才不要加入你们的飞车联盟
I don't want to join your biker alliance
飞车小组  更别提飞车协会了
your outfit, or your fellowship
那我们的联合体呢
What about our coalition?
不好说
I don't know
联合体挺排外的
That one's pretty exclusive
直接把你登记为待定吧
We'll just pencil you down as undecided
嗨  蟹老板
Hi, Mr. Krabs
我们是裤头村坏小子
We're the Bikini Bottom bad boys
坏到骨子里了
and we're bad to the bone
应该挺棒的
This should be great
到时那伙飞车党肯定能胃口大开
Those bikers can work up an appetite
毕竟他们会在停车场暴打你们
beating you up in the parking lot
然后就会来饱餐一顿美味的蟹黄堡了
Then, they can fill up on delicious Krabby Patties
然后再来暴打你们
Then, they can beat you up again
得了吧  蟹老板
Please, Mr. Krabs
我们是要赶走那伙飞车党
We're going to run off those bikers
拯救蟹堡王的
and save the krusty krab
你们休想赶走我的金主顾客
You're not running off any of me paying customers
那就留着被他们在停车场暴打吧
You can stay and get beaten up in the parking lot
爱走不走
if you wish
然后我们就能拯救裤头村了吗
Then can we save the town?
你们就没想过
Has it ever crossed your mind
自己很有可能会白忙活一场吗
that you might be getting all worked up over nothing?
章鱼哥  我什么时候有反应过激过
Squidward, when have I ever been known to overreact?
章鱼哥
Squidward
我们餐巾纸没有了
We're out of napkins
餐巾纸没有了
Out of napkins
章鱼哥
Squidward
我不小心摘掉了
I accidentally removed
床垫上面写着依法不得摘除的标签
the "do not remove by penalty of law" tag on my mattress
[ 只有厂商不得摘除，消费者可摘除 ]
掩护我
Hide me
章鱼哥
Squidward
我瞎了
I've gone blind
谢了  章鱼哥
Thanks, Squidward
海绵宝宝  你碰啥事都能过激
SpongeBob, you always overreact to everything
这就是你众多烦人的特点之一
It's one of your many annoying traits
我  烦人吗
Me, annoying?
才怪呢
Yeah, right
你说啥都是错的  海绵宝宝
You are so wrong about everything, SpongeBob
我只能说唯一完完全全确定的就是
that the only thing I am completely sure about
没有飞车党在朝这边开过来
is that there is no motorcycle gang headed this way
那是什么
What was that?
大家注意看
Ahoy, there, mateys
一大伙摩托车要开过来了
Motorized vehicles coming over the horizon
什么
What?
给我
Give me that
别光站那啊
Don't just stand there--
救救我们
save us
派大星  虽然我知道似乎要完蛋了
Patrick, I know this looks like the end
但我跟你可以共度难关
but you and I can get through anything
只要我们能齐心协力
as long as we do it together
派大星
Patrick?
Patrick
公交站
只剩咱们俩了  章鱼哥
Well, it's just you and me, Squidward
但我想让你知道  我们能共度难关
But I want you to know we can get through this
只要我们
as long as we--
恐慌
Panic
快逃命啊
Run for your lives
坏东西要来了
The wild ones are coming
坏东西吗
The wild ones?
梅布尔  叫小朋友过来
Mabel, get the kids
亲爱的  我餐巾纸拿来了
Honey, I got the napkins
这回我错过什么了
What have I missed this time?
拜托  别杀我
Please, don't kill me
我想加入你们
I want to join you
我一生都梦想着要加入飞车党
It's been my life-long dream
to be a member of a motorcycle gang
连坏东西夹克衫我都缝好了
I even knitted my own wild ones jacket
我要飞车活下去
I want to ride to live
我活着就要飞车
I live to ride
拜托饶了我吧
Please, spare me
你们要什么  我就做什么
I'll do whatever you want
我一定会背叛我朋友跟邻居
I'll betray my friends and neighbors
饶我一命吧
Just let me live
说什么  小姑娘
What's that, missy?
什么
What?
你好
Howdy
我们是好东西
We're the mild ones
好
Mild
东西
ones?
把我衣服上的M还回来
Give me back my "m"
大伙儿走吧
Let's go, boys
你们就不想花钱吗
Don't you want to spend any money?
你就不想亲亲我裤子后裆吗
Don't you want to kiss the seat of my pants?
飞车吧
Let's ride
再见
Good-bye
他们好像还挺和善的
They seemed really nice
章鱼哥呢
Where's Squidward?
飞车活下去
Ride to live
活着就飞车
and live to ride
化敌为友
分镜总监
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
技术总监
动画总监
制片指导
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
不对
No--
不可能
impossible
我都数钱数了十几次了
I must have counted me money a dozen times
结果还是少了
and it still comes up short
利润
Profits
都
are
下滑了
down
我真可怜自己
I feel sorry for meself
你这一餐要配饮料吗
Would you like a drink with that order?
不用  谢了
No thanks
我进门前就买了杯新上市的海草奶昔
I got me one of those new kelpshakes
before I came in here
总共两块钱
That comes out to $2.00 even
真是实惠
What a steal
怎么
What the--
那家伙怎么没买
why didn't that guy order
汽水机的天价饮料配蟹黄堡吃
a deliciously overpriced fountain beverage
with his Krabby Patty?
蟹老板  我们几天都没卖出一杯汽水
Mr. Krabs, we haven't sold a single soda in days
什么
What?
为什么
Why not?
小子  够了
All right, boy, it's done
再不小心  整杯都会被你吸进食道里
You're going to suck the whole cup down your gullet
if you're not careful
抱歉  蟹老板
Sorry, Mr. Krabs
只是这海草奶昔真是太好喝了
It's just that these kelpshakes taste so good
海草奶昔
海草奶昔吗
Kelpshake?
看看你四周
Look around you
大家都在畅饮美味的海草奶昔
Everyone's enjoying a delicious kelpshake
我马上回来  蟹老板
I'll be right back, Mr. Krabs
我去续杯了
I'm going to get a refill
续杯
Refill?
给我得了
That's it
大家都听好
Listen up, everybody
新规定
New rule--
严禁外带饮料
no outside drinks
绝不例外
No exceptions
说得好啊
That's telling 'em
我最好去查个水落石出
I better get to the bottom of this
海草奶昔
一家新店
A new store
开在我的地盘
On my block
抢走了我的客人
Taking my customers
珍珍
Pearl
我的宝贝女儿
Me own flesh and blood
你怎么能这样对你老爸
How could you do this to your papa?
你说什么玩意  老爸
What are you talking about, dad?
我说的就是这个
I'm talking about this
一旦品尝到一杯海草奶昔的秘密精华
Once you taste the secret goodness of a kelpshake--
就肯定会喝上不止一杯
You can't have just one
快给我
Give me that
自己买去
Buy your own
我一分钱都不会给他们
Why, I wouldn't give them a cent
我真为你遗憾
I feel sorry for you
然后你就会理解我了
Then you do understand me
爸
Dad
你害我丢脸了
You're embarrassing me
走开
Get away
不要
Oh, no
我诅咒你  新开的海草奶昔店
Confound you, new kelpshake store
你有什么秘密
What's your secret?
还真是
Of course
痞老板
Plankton
他一定就是幕后黑手
I bet he's behind this
我就知道你是幕后黑手
I knew you were behind this
不好意思
Pardon me
我没干坏事
I've done nothing wrong
那你怎么解释这个
Then how do you explain this?
我的天啊
Holy moly
那是怎么一回事
How did that happen?
少给我装傻了  痞老板
Don't try that with me, Plankton
这新店害我生意一落千丈
This new store is ruining me business
真的吗
Really?
等一下
Wait a minute
应该是我害你没生意才对
That's my job
该死
Blast it
跟这小丑竞争就已经够糟了
It's bad enough I have to compete with this joker
结果又多了个这玩意
Now, there's this?
海草奶昔
Kelpshakes
看来你并不是幕后黑手啊
I guess you're really not behind this after all
痞老板
Plankton
他们有
They have
秘密配方
A secret formula
不要
No
别又来个秘密
Not another secret
要是有秘密  我就非摸清楚不可
And if there's a secret, I want to know about it
海之霸
它们在增殖
They're multiplying
它们每家街角都开了
Why, they're on every corner
个个街区都开了
Block after block
到处都是
They're everywhere
必须得出手办了这店
We've got to do something about this
你确定这样有用吗
You sure this is going to work?
照计划走就是了
Just stick to the plan
来看看
Let's see
仅限员工
找到了
There you are
痞老板  我好像找到厨房了
Plankton, I think I found the kitchen
那就开搞吧
Let's do this thing
来了
Here goes
抱歉
Sorry
我有一点点
I got a little bit of--
好滋味
我的眼睛
My eye
应该是甩掉他了
I think we lost him
你还有没有什么好办法
Well, you got any more bright ideas?
当然有了
Of course I do
准备好没  痞老板
All set, Plankton?
不信你也得信
You better believe it
我发明的这高能机械臂
This high-powered mechanical bio-arm I invented
应该轻轻松松就能扒开这餐厅的大门
should pry those restaurant doors open nice and easy
怎么回事
What the barnacles?
动啊  你这垃圾
Come on, you piece of garbage
不要
Oh, no
我投降  我投降
Uncle, uncle
要想把事情做好
If you want anything done right
就得亲自来做
you got to do it yourself
我的背
Me back
老螃蟹
Krabs
小点声
Pipe down
吵醒看门狗  计划就泡汤了
You're going to soil our plans if you wake the watchdog
那个没关系
Never mind that
那吵醒海绵宝宝怎么办
What about SpongeBob?
嗨  蟹老板
Hi, Mr. Krabs
嗨
Hi--
痞老板
Plankton?
蟹老板  我有点搞不懂
Mr. Krabs, I'm a little confused
你跟痞老板不是死对头吗
Don't you and Plankton hate each other?
那当然了
Of course we do
那
Then
他咋被你捏拳头里了
Why is he in your fist?
我们
We've
一起办商业活动
Gone into business together
跟你说吧  海绵宝宝
You see, SpongeBob
我们受聘来
we were hired to, uh
修理这扇门
fix this door
现在我们得去修理屋顶了
And now, we have to fix the roof
没错
That's right
我们得去修理屋顶
We got to fix the roof
它
It's--
it's--
漏水了
it's leaking
那就祝你们好运
Well, good luck with that
再见
See ya
继续凿  老螃蟹
Keep her going, Krabs
照这速度  海草奶昔秘方到手
At this rate, we'll have the kelpshakes recipe
肯定是一眨眼
faster than you can say--
离你们自燃还剩三秒钟
You have 3 seconds until spontaneous combustion
快逃
Let's beat it
没开玩笑
No kidding
等一下
Wait
你忘了
You forgot--
我认输了  老螃蟹
I'm throwing in the towel, Krabs
整了这么多复杂的计划都泡汤了
All these convoluted plans are getting us nowhere
更有甚者
And to top it all off
出事的就只有我
I'm the only one who's taking the heat
你那是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
我都没看到你上前线
I don't see you on the front lines
好吧  那就让我把活都干了
Sure, let me do all the work
你自个袖手旁观当个肥猩猩得了
while you just sit back like the fat gorilla you are
你管谁叫猩猩
Who are you calling a gorilla
你个单细胞独眼底栖生物
you one-celled, one-eyed bottom-feeder?
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
你想要海草奶昔的话
if you want a kelpshake
干嘛不直接去买一杯呢
why don't you just buy one?
买一杯
Buy one?
来杯海草奶昔
I'll have one kelpshake, please
感觉这样不太好啊  痞老板
I don't know about this, Plankton
很简单的
It's easy
只要微笑  给收银员钱就行了
Just smile and hand the cashier the money
需要什么服务
Can I help you?
祝你好运
Good luck
你好
Hi, there
能来杯海草奶昔吗
Could I get one kelpshake?
可以
Sure
总共一块钱
That will be $1.00
好的
Ok
谢谢
Thank you
先生
Sir?
请你把钱放开
Please let go of the bill
松手啊
Release your grip, man
快啊
Do it
请慢用
Enjoy
谢了
Thanks
真不敢相信我们成功了
I can't believe we did it
信就信吧  老螃蟹
Believe it, Krabs
咱们快去实验室
Now, let's get to the lab
查清楚这东西到底什么成分
and find out what this stuff is made of
里面有什么秘密配料  凯伦
What's the secret ingredient, Karen?
看上去主要成分就只是
Well, it appears that the main ingredient is
海草汁
kelp juice
只有海草汁吗
Just kelp juice?
原来这一直以来
And to think, this whole time
我自个儿就可以卖这玩意了
I could have been selling these meself
你
You?
那我呢
What about me?
要是有谁卖这个赚钱  就该是我才对
If anyone, I deserve to make a buck selling this stuff
想得美  小不点
No way, pipsqueak
这摇钱树是我的
This gold mine is mine
我绝不让你得逞
Not if I can help it
想得美
Nice try
我要是你  就不会喝的
I wouldn't do that if I were you
还有一样成分
There's another ingredient
这可是我花钱买来的
I paid good money for this thing
我当然要喝了
Of course I'm going to drink it
怎么
What the--
不懂这玩意有啥了不起的
I don't get what the big deal is
简直跟湿乎乎的运动袜一个味道
This tastes like a wet gym sock
是吗
Really?
让我尝尝看
Let me try that
其实还有一小股猛烈的余味
Actually, there is a bit of a pungent aftertaste
还真是
You're right
还算不错
This ain't half bad
真是太神了
This is amazing
那就别独吞
Well, don't be selfish
好耶
Oh, yeah
不好
Oh, no
蟹老板  咱们都喝光了
Krabs, we're all out of juice
那就得再去买
Then we got to get more
你们犯了天大的错误
You're making a big mistake
放屁
Phooey
你都不知道自己在说什么
You don't know what you're talking about
海草奶昔  海草奶昔
Kelpshake, kelpshake
我好爱海草奶昔
oh, how I love a kelpshake
我是怎么了
What's happening to me?
海草奶昔店都已经关停了
They've shut down the kelpshakes restaurants
永久关停
清理这些有害材料要花好几十年
It will take decades
to clean this hazardous material up
我真为喝了这玩意的人遗憾
I sure feel sorry for whoever drank this
看看我们
Look at us
这下我们该怎么办
Now what are we going to do?
我不知道你要怎么办
I don't know about you
但我要继续做我最拿手的事
But I'm going back to what I do best--
偷你秘方
stealing your recipe
等一下
Wait a minute
痞老板
Plankton
快到我这来
Come to papa
给我站住
Hold it right there
你哪都别想去
You're not going anywhere
让你十秒钟先跑
Without a 10-second head start
回家的感觉真好
It's good to be home
还真是
You said it
我就爱被人讨厌
I love being hated
给我回来  你这小鼻屎
Get back here, you little booger